It's August 5, 2010.
2010年8月5日，
A massive collapse at the San José Copper Mine in Northern Chile
在智利北部的圣何塞铜矿， 一场巨大的坍塌
has left 33 men trapped half a mile -- that's two Empire State Buildings --
使得33个人被困在了半英里深的地下 ——相当于两个帝国大厦的深度——
below some of the hardest rock in the world.
头顶是世界上最坚硬的岩石。
They will find their way to a small refuge designed for this purpose,
被困人员会前往一个 预先设计好的小型避难所，
where they will find intense heat, filth
那里酷热，肮脏，
and about enough food for two men for 10 days.
保存着只够两个人维持10天的食物。
Aboveground, it doesn't take long
地面上的专家很快就发现，
for the experts to figure out that there is no solution.
他们找不出可行的营救方案。
No drilling technology in the industry is capable of getting through rock
没有任何现成的钻孔技术 能够在有限的时间内
that hard and that deep
在这样的深度打通如此坚硬的石头，
fast enough to save their lives.
将被困人员活着救出来。
It's not exactly clear where the refuge is.
人们不确定地下避难所的位置，
It's not even clear if the miners are alive.
也不确定矿工们是否还活着。
And it's not even clear who's in charge.
甚至都不知道相关负责人是谁。
Yet, within 70 days, all 33 of these men will be brought to the surface alive.
但是，在70天内， 所有33人都会活着回到地面。
This remarkable story is a case study
这一非凡的故事，是一起关于
in the power of teaming.
团队合作力量的案例分析。
So what's "teaming"?
那么“团队合作”是什么？
Teaming is teamwork on the fly.
团队合作是高效的互相配合。
It's coordinating and collaborating with people
它是与各种各样的人 进行协调和合作，
across boundaries of all kinds --
跨过各种障碍——
expertise, distance, time zone, you name it --
专业知识，距离，时区， 所有你能想到的——
to get work done.
来完成工作。
Think of your favorite sports team, because this is different.
对比你最喜欢的运动队， 因为这是不一样的。
Sports teams work together: that magic, those game-saving plays.
运动队需要协作：那种魔力， 那些扭转局势的操作。
Now, sports teams win because they practice.
不过运动队会获胜， 是因为他们平时在练习。
But you can only practice if you have the same members over time.
但你只能在有着同样队友的 情况下进行那样的练习。
And so you can think of teaming ...
所以你可以想想团队合作……
Sports teams embody the definition of a team,
运动队符合一个队伍的定义，
the formal definition.
正式的定义。
It's a stable, bounded, reasonably small group of people
这是一组稳定，联系着的， 相对比较小的一组人。
who are interdependent in achieving a shared outcome.
他们互相依靠，以达到共享的结果。
You can think of teaming as a kind of pickup game in the park,
你可以把团队合作想成 在公园里的临时发起的比赛，
in contrast to the formal, well-practiced team.
而非专业的，训练充足的队伍。
Now, which one is going to win in a playoff?
那么，哪一队会在比赛中胜出呢？
The answer is obvious.
答案显而易见。
So why do I study teaming?
所以我为什么要研究团队合作呢？
It's because it's the way more and more of us have to work today.
因为在今天，我们越来越多地 需要以这种方式工作。
With 24/7 global fast-paced operations,
在每天24小时运营的 快节奏的全球企业中，
crazy shifting schedules
有着疯狂改变的计划表，
and ever-narrower expertise,
和越发细分的专业，
more and more of us have to work with different people all the time
越来越多的时候，我们需要 和其他不同的人
to get our work done.
一起合作，来完成工作。
We don't have the luxury of stable teams.
我们无法奢望一个稳定的团队。
Now, when you can have that luxury, by all means do it.
如果可以的话，务必要这样做。
But increasingly for a lot of the work we do today,
但今天的许多工作
we don't have that option.
却无法提供这样的条件。
One place where this is true is hospitals.
比如，医院。
This is where I've done a lot of my research over the years.
多年来我的很多研究 都是在这里进行的。
So it turns out hospitals have to be open 24/7.
医院必须24小时开放。
And patients -- well, they're all different.
而病人们——他们的情况各不相同。
They're all different in complicated and unique ways.
以独特而复杂的方式不同。
The average hospitalized patient is seen by 60 or so different caregivers
平均每个病人在住院期间
throughout his stay.
会被60多人照看。
They come from different shifts, different specialties,
他们来自不同班次，
different areas of expertise,
有着不同的背景和专业，
and they may not even know each other's name.
可能甚至都不知道彼此的名字。
But they have to coordinate in order for the patient to get great care.
但为了病人他们必须互相合作。
And when they don't, the results can be tragic.
而如果他们不这样做， 就会有惨剧发生。
Of course, in teaming, the stakes aren't always life and death.
当然，在团队合作中， 并不总是涉及生死。
Consider what it takes to create an animated film,
想想当你需要做 一部获奖的动画电影时
an award-winning animated film.
会经历什么。
I had the good fortune to go to Disney Animation
我有幸去过迪士尼动画公司，
and study over 900 scientists, artists,
并且研究了超过900位 科学家和艺术家，
storytellers, computer scientists
故事讲述人，电脑专家，
as they teamed up in constantly changing configurations
研究他们如何在不断变化的 人员配置中通过团队合作
to create amazing outcomes like "Frozen."
来制造出像《冰雪奇缘》 一样伟大的作品。
They just work together, and never the same group twice,
他们就是在一起工作， 从来没有两组人是同样的，
not knowing what's going to happen next.
谁都不知道接下来会发生什么。
Now, taking care of patients in the emergency room
在急救室照顾病人
and designing an animated film
与设计动画电影
are obviously very different work.
显然是截然不同的工作。
Yet underneath the differences, they have a lot in common.
但在差异之下，他们 又有很多相似之处。
You have to get different expertise at different times,
你必须在不同的时间 获得不同的专业知识，
you don't have fixed roles, you don't have fixed deliverables,
你没有固定角色，没有固定交付任务，
you're going to be doing a lot of things that have never been done before,
你会做一些你从未做过的事情，
and you can't do it in a stable team.
还不能在一个固定团队中实现。
Now, this way of working isn't easy,
这种工作方式并不简单，
but as I said, it's more and more the way many of us have to work,
但像我说的，这是越来越多的人 必需的工作方式，
so we have to understand it.
所以我们必须理解它。
And I would argue that it's especially needed
我认为，对于复杂和不可预测的工作
for work that's complex and unpredictable
和解决大问题来说，
and for solving big problems.
这是特别必要的。
Paul Polman, the Unilever CEO, put this really well
联合利华首席执行官 保罗 · 波尔曼说得很好，
when he said, "The issues we face today are so big and so challenging,
他说：“我们今天面临的问题 是如此巨大，如此具有挑战性，
it becomes quite clear we can't do it alone,
很明显，我们不能单独行动，
and so there is a certain humility in knowing you have to invite people in."
所以在知道你必须邀请人们进来的 时候，你会有一种谦逊的态度。”
Issues like food or water scarcity cannot be done by individuals,
像粮食和水资源短缺这样的问题 是不能由个人来解决的，
even by single companies,
甚至是单个公司，
even by single sectors.
单个部门。
So we're reaching out to team across big teaming,
所以我们正在与团队进行大的合作，
grand-scale teaming.
大规模的合作。
Take the quest for smart cities.
以智慧城市为例。
Maybe you've seen some of the rhetoric:
也许你见过一些修辞：
mixed-use designs, zero net energy buildings,
多功能设计，零能耗建筑，
smart mobility,
智能移动，
green, livable, wonderful cities.
绿色宜居，美好的城市。
We have the vocabulary, we have the visions,
我们有词汇，我们有愿景，
not to mention the need.
更别说需求。
We have the technology.
我们有技术。
Two megatrends --
有两个大趋势——
urbanization, we're fast becoming a more urban planet,
城市化，我们快速的变成 越发城市化的星球，
and climate change --
以及气候变化——
have been increasingly pointing to cities
它们越来越多的指向城市，
as a crucial target for innovation.
成为创新的关键目标。
And now around the world in various locations,
而现在在世界各地不同的地点，
people have been teaming up
人们组成团队
to design and try to create green, livable, smart cities.
来设计和尝试创造 绿色，宜居，智能的城市。
It's a massive innovation challenge.
这是个巨大的创新挑战。
To understand it better,
为了更好理解这点，
I studied a start-up -- a smart-city software start-up --
我研究了一家初创公司—— 一家智能城市的软件初创公司——
as it teamed up with a real estate developer,
它与一个房地产开发商，
some civil engineers,
一些土木工程师，
a mayor,
一个市长，
an architect, some builders, some tech companies.
一个建筑师，一些建筑商， 和一些科技公司合作。
Their goal was to build a demo smart city from scratch.
他们的目标是从零开始建立一个 演示版的智能城市。
OK. Five years into the project, not a whole lot had happened.
好的。项目进行了五年， 并没有多大进度。
Six years, still no ground broken.
六年，仍然没有破土动工。
It seemed that teaming across industry boundaries
似乎跨产业的团队合作
was really, really hard.
非常，非常难。
OK, so ...
好的。那么……
We had inadvertently discovered
我们在这一项目中
what I call "professional culture clash" with this project.
无意间发现了我称之为 “职业文化冲突”的现象。
You know, software engineers and real estate developers
软件工程师和房地产开发商
think differently --
有着不同的思维——
really differently:
非常不同：
different values, different time frames -- time frames is a big one --
不同价值观，不同的时间框架—— 时间框架是很重要的一点——
and different jargon, different language.
以及不同的行话，不同的语言。
And so they don't always see eye to eye.
所以他们并不总是意见一致。
I think this is a bigger problem than most of us realize.
我认为这是我们大多数人都没有 意识到的一个更大的问题。
In fact, I think professional culture clash
事实上，我认为专业间的文化冲突
is a major barrier to building the future that we aspire to build.
是建设我们渴望建立的 未来的主要障碍。
And so it becomes a problem that we have to understand,
这就变成了一个 我们必须理解的问题，
a problem that we have to figure out how to crack.
一个我们必须找到解决方法的问题。
So how do you make sure teaming goes well, especially big teaming?
那么，你如何才能确保团队合作能够 顺利进行，尤其是大团队？
This is the question I've been trying to solve for a number of years
这就是我在许多年的研究中，
in many different workplaces
在不同的工作场所
with my research.
尝试解决的问题。
Now, to begin to get just a glimpse of the answer to this question,
要想对这个问题有初步的了解，
let's go back to Chile.
让我们回到智利。
In Chile, we witnessed 10 weeks of teaming
在智利，我们见证了 10周的团队合作，
by hundreds of individuals
涉及到几百位来自
from different professions, different companies,
不同职业，不同公司，
different sectors, even different nations.
不同领域，甚至不同国家的人。
And as this process unfolded,
而随着这个过程的展开，
they had lots of ideas, they tried many things,
他们有了很多想法， 进行了多次尝试，
they experimented, they failed,
他们实验了，又失败了，
they experienced devastating daily failure,
他们每天都经历着毁灭性的失败，
but they picked up, persevered,
但又会爬起来，坚持着，
and went on forward.
继续前进。
And really, what we witnessed there
而事实上，我们所看到的是，
was they were able to be humble
面对未来真正的挑战，
in the face of the very real challenge ahead,
他们能够保持谦逊，
curious -- all of these diverse individuals,
充满好奇——所有这些不同的人，
diverse expertise especially, nationality as well,
尤其是有着不同的专业和国籍，
were quite curious about what each other brings.
都对彼此带来的东西很好奇。
And they were willing to take risks to learn fast what might work.
而且他们愿意承担风险来了解 哪些方法可能有效。
And ultimately, 17 days into this remarkable story,
而最终，在这个故事发生的第17天，
ideas came from everywhere.
来自世界各地的点子接踵而至。
They came from André Sougarret, who is a brilliant mining engineer
它们来自安德烈 · 苏加瑞特， 他是一个杰出的采矿工程师，
who was appointed by the government to lead the rescue.
受政府指派领导救援。
They came from NASA.
它们来自美国国家航空航天局。
They came from Chilean Special Forces.
它们来自智利特种部队。
They came from volunteers around the world.
它们来自全世界的志愿者们。
And while many of us, including myself, watched from afar,
而当我们中的许多人， 包括我自己，从远处观察着，
these folks made slow, painful progress through the rock.
这些人正在岩石中 缓慢而痛苦地前进。
On the 17th day, they broke through to the refuge.
在第17天，他们成功进入了避难所。
It's just a remarkable moment.
这是个激动人心的时刻。
And with just a very small incision, they were able to find it
而只用一个小小的切口，他们便能
through a bunch of experimental techniques.
利用许多实验技巧来找到避难所。
And then for the next 53 days,
而之后的53天里，
that narrow lifeline would be the path
这一狭窄的生命通道会成为
where food and medicine and communication would travel,
食物、药品与交流的通道，
while aboveground, for 53 more days, they continued the teaming
而在地上，在53天里， 他们继续着团队合作，
to find a way to create a much larger hole
来找出一个制造更大洞口的方法，
and also to design a capsule.
并且设计一个舱室。
This is the capsule.
这就是那个舱室。
And then on the 69th day,
而之后，在第69天，
over 22 painstaking hours,
经历了超过22个小时痛苦的努力，
they managed to pull the miners out one by one.
他们终于能够将矿工们 一个一个拉出来。
So how did they overcome professional culture clash?
那么他们究竟是如何克服 职业文化冲突的呢？
I would say in a word, it's leadership, but let me be more specific.
我会用一个词概括：领导力。 不过让我更详细的解释一下。
When teaming works,
当团队合作顺利时，
you can be sure that some leaders,
你可以肯定有些领导者，
leaders at all levels,
不同层级的领导者，
have been crystal clear that they don't have the answers.
非常清楚他们自己没有答案。
Let's call this "situational humility."
让我们把这称为“情境谦虚”。
It's appropriate humility.
这是适当的谦逊。
We don't know how to do it.
我们不知道该怎样做。
You can be sure, as I said before, people were very curious,
你可以确定，就像我之前 说的一样，人们很好奇，
and this situational humility
而这一情境中的谦虚
combined with curiosity
与好奇心结合起来，
creates a sense of psychological safety
创造了一种心理安全感，
that allows you take risks with strangers,
使得你可以与陌生人 一起承担风险。
because let's face it: it's hard to speak up, right?
因为我们要直面它： 开口总是很难，对吧？
It's hard to ask for help.
寻求帮助绝非易事。
It's hard to offer an idea that might be a stupid idea
如果你并不是很了解别人，
if you don't know people very well.
你很难说出一个可能愚蠢的想法。
You need psychological safety to do that.
你需要心理安全感来这么做。
They overcame what I like to call the basic human challenge:
他们跨越了我称作 基本人类挑战的东西：
it's hard to learn if you already know.
如果你已经知道了， 就很难继续学习。
And unfortunately, we're hardwired to think we know.
而不幸的是，我们天生就 倾向于认为自己知道。
And so we've got to remind ourselves -- and we can do it --
所以，我们需要提醒自己—— 我们能做到这点——
to be curious;
要充满好奇心；
to be curious about what others bring.
要好奇其他人能带来的东西。
And that curiosity can also spawn a kind of generosity of interpretation.
这种好奇心也能产生 一种慷慨的解释。
But there's another barrier, and you all know it.
但还有另一个障碍， 而你们都知道它。
You wouldn't be in this room if you didn't know it.
如果你不知道， 你就不会在这个房间里。
And to explain it, I'm going to quote from the movie "The Paper Chase."
而要想解释它，我想引用电影 《力争上游》里的一句话：
This, by the way, is what Hollywood thinks
顺便说一句，这是好莱坞认为的
a Harvard professor is supposed to look like.
一个哈佛教授应该具备的形象。
You be the judge.
你们自行评判。
The professor in this famous scene,
在这一著名场景中的教授，
he's welcoming the new 1L class,
他正在欢迎新的学生，
and he says, "Look to your left. Look to your right.
而他说：“朝左看看。朝右看看。
one of you won't be here next year."
你们中的一个明年不会在这里了。”
What message did they hear? "It's me or you."
他们听到了什么消息呢？ “不是我就是你。”
For me to succeed, you must fail.
如果我要成功，你必须失败。
Now, I don't think too many organizations welcome newcomers that way anymore,
现在，我并不认为许多组织 会像那样欢迎新人了，
but still, many times people arrive with that message of scarcity anyway.
不过，许多时候，人们在进入组织时 依然会听到这条关于稀缺性的信息。
It's me or you.
不是我就是你。
It's awfully hard to team if you inadvertently see others as competitors.
如果你不小心将别人视为竞争对手， 那你就很难与他们合作。
So we have to overcome that one as well,
所以我们也需要克服这一点。
and when we do, the results can be awesome.
而当我们这样做的时候， 结果会非常棒。
Abraham Lincoln said once,
亚伯拉罕 · 林肯曾经说过：
"I don't like that man very much. I must get to know him better."
“我不太喜欢那个人。 我必须更好地了解他。”
Think about that --
想想看——
I don't like him, that means I don't know him well enough.
我不喜欢他，这意味着 我对他不够了解。
It's extraordinary.
多么伟大的想法。
This is the mindset, I have to say,
这是一种心态，我不得不说，
this is the mindset you need for effective teaming.
这是你在进行有效合作时 所需要的心态。
In our silos, we can get things done.
在我们的筒仓里， 我们可以把事情做完。
But when we step back and reach out and reach across,
但当我们退后一步，伸出手去，
miracles can happen.
奇迹就能发生。
Miners can be rescued,
矿工们可以获救，
patients can be saved,
病人们能得救，
beautiful films can be created.
美丽的电影能被制造出来。
To get there, I think there's no better advice than this:
为了达到这个目标， 我认为没有比这更好的建议了：
look to your left, look to your right.
向左看，向右看。
How quickly can you find the unique talents, skills
你能多快地找到你的邻居 所拥有的独特才华、
and hopes of your neighbor,
技能和愿景，
and how quickly, in turn, can you convey what you bring?
又能多快地传达出 你想要传递的信息？
Because for us to team up to build the future we know we can create
因为对于我们来说，为了建立一个 我们知道可以通过集体，
that none of us can do alone,
而非个人所能创造的未来，
that's the mindset we need.
这就是我们需要的心态。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）